Guide to the Mick Moloney Irish-American Music and Popular Culture Field Recordings AIA.031.002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Mick Moloney Irish-American Music and Popular Culture Field Recordings
1956-2009
1974-1997
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Moloney, Mick, 1944-
AIA.031.002
59.54 Linear Feet in 40 compact disc boxes, 10 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, and 33 record cartons.
1.98 Gigabytes in 12 computer files
The Mick Moloney Irish-American Music and Popular Culture Field Recordings consists of field recordings made and collected by Dr. Mick Moloney in the course of his career as a folklorist, producer, musician, and academic. The recordings include interviews and private performances, commercial recording sessions, rehearsals, demos, concert performances, informal group sessions, ceilis, competitions, lectures, and broadcasts. The field recordings range in date from 1956-2001. The majority of the original tapes are ¼″ reel-to-reels and audio cassettes, but also include some 8, 16 and 24-track master reels. Some of the recordings have been digitized. The collection also includes written inventories containing metadata pertaining to recordings found within the collection.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
The Field Recordings is a subcollection of the Mick Moloney Irish-American Music and Popular Culture Collection. Other subcollections include Commercial Records (AIA 031.001), the Mick Moloney Papers (AIA 031.003), and Irish Americana (AIA 031.004).
Other collections that document the Irish-American musical scene include the Dorothy Hayden Cudahy Irish Memories Collection (AIA 001) and the Susan McKeown Papers (AIA 032).
Biographical Note
Dr. Mick Moloney (1944-2022) was a musician, folklorist, and Global Distinguished Professor of Music and Irish Studies at New York University. He immigrated to the United States in 1973, earning a Ph.D. in folklore and folklife from the University of Pennsylvania. He recorded and produced over forty albums of traditional music, acted as advisor for scores of festivals and concerts, and served as artistic director for the musical ensemble, The Green Fields of America. In 1999, Moloney was awarded the National Heritage Award of the National Endowment of the Arts, the highest official honor of traditional artist can receive in the United States.
Moloney was the author of Far from the Shamrock Shore (2002) and numerous essays on Irish music and musical culture, and the co-editor of Close to the Floor: Irish Dance from the Boreen to Broadway (2009).
Sources:
Steve Winnick, "From Limerick Rake to Solid Man: The Musical Life of Mick Moloney," Dirty Linen, No. 48 (October/November 1993)
1999 NEA National Heritage Fellowships: http://www.nea.gov/honors/heritage/fellows/fellow.php?id=1999_11
Mick Moloney, Musician and Folklorist: http://www.mickmoloney.com
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to some audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact special.collections@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research without restrictions.
Scope and Contents
The Mick Moloney Irish-American Music and Popular Culture Field Recordings document the Irish-American traditional music scene between 1956 and 2001 (bulk dates 1974 to 1997). The collection is diverse in its musical styles and content, making it an informative resource for scholars and students of the Irish-American experience. The collection features 115 formal and informal interviews, as well as hundreds of musical performances from instrumental virtuosi, including a significant number of women musicians, ranging from live concert performances to recording and informal sessions. Additionally, the collection uniquely documents Mick Moloney's own musical and academic career by reflecting the types of materials that interested him and he felt compelled to collect. The collection consists primarily of ¼″ reel-to-reels and audio cassettes, but also includes some 8, 16 and 24-track master reels.
Series III. Interview Information Sheets and Series IV. Audio Inventories for Grammy Preservation Project consists of paper documents relating to the audio materials in this collection. Both the "Interview Information Sheets" and "Grammy Preservation Project" documents provide background information and basic metadata about the tapes that were digitized in 2007 and 2008 by archiving and preservation grants from the Grammy Foundation.
Custodial History
New York University's Division of Libraries, in conjunction with Glucksman Ireland House at New York University, purchased the Mick Moloney Collection for the Archives of Irish America in 2006. Until the Collection was transferred to New York University, under the supervision of Dr. Michael Nash, Head of the Tamiment Library, the materials were stored in Dr. Moloney's house in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. The accession numbers associated with this collection are 2006.071, 2010.019, and 2010.073.
In September 2022, Elizabeth Carron, Senior Accessioning Archivist at the Boston College Burns Library, transferred four optical discs of recordings copied from Moloney's original cassettes to New York University. These items were deaccessioned from Boston College's Irish Music Archives at the discretion of Curator Beth Sweeney. The accession number associated with this transfer is 2023.026.
Arrangement
The Mick Moloney Irish-American Music and Popular Culture Field Recordings is arranged in two series, as follows:
Series I. Private Performances
Series II. Public Performances
Series III. Interview Information Sheets
Series IV. Audio Inventories for Grammy Preservation Project
Series I and II are further arranged alphabetically by surname. Series III and IV also list performers by their surname, however, they are arranged in the original order in which the documents were received.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
An additional accession was donated by Mick Moloney in 2018, the accession number associated with this gift is 2018.118.
Private performance.; Practice (rehearsal).; Interviews.; Irish Americans.; Music schools.; Compilation.; Composition (Music); Concerts.; Demonstrations (presentation events).; Detroit (Mich.); Irish Americans -- Music.; Recording session.; San Francisco (Calif.); Saint Paul (Minn.); Washington (D.C.); Workshops (seminars); Oral history.; Philadelphia (Pa.); Music |x Competitions.; New York (N.Y.).; Music festivals.; Irish -- Songs and music.; Irish -- Music; Irish Americans -- Social life and customs.; Broadcasts.; Boston (Mass.); Chicago (Ill.); Ceili.; Competitions.; Cleveland (Ohio); O'Donnell, Eugene, 1932-; Britton, Tim; McGreevy, Johnny, 1919-; McComiskey, Billy; McGlynn, Sean; Rafferty, Mike, 1926-; Egan, Seamus, 1969-; Keane, Jimmy; Carroll, Liz, 1957-; Ivers, Eileen; Neary, Eleanor Kane, 1915-1993; O'Connell, Robbie; Coen, Jack; Coen, Charlie, Fr., 1934-; Ochs, Bill; Keane, James, 1948-; Cahill, Eddie
- Series I: Private Performances, 1970-1992, circa 1970-Jan 27, 1992
  Scope and Content Note
  Private Performances include interviews, recording sessions, rehearsals and demos with both recording veterans and musicians just beginning their careers. Several of the artists recorded (Kevin Burke, Liz Carroll, Jack Coen, Donny Golden, Michael Flatley, Joe Heaney, Mick Moloney, Martin Mulvihill, Joe Shannon) were subsequently awarded National Heritage Fellowships from the National Endowment for the Arts.
  During his earliest years in the United States (1976-1980) Mick Moloney sought out musicians in the Boston, Chicago, Detroit, New York and Philadelphia areas. Among the first was Co. Cavan fiddler Ed Reavy (1897-1988), whose compositions pervade the twentieth-century Irish traditional music repertoire, recorded in Philadelphia in 1974, 1977 and 1979. Flute player Eddie Cahill (b. 1929) was recorded on nine separate occasions in 1977 and 1978. Then one of the leading proponents of the Sligo-style of playing that had come to dominate Irish traditional music due to the influence of 78rpm recordings, Cahill (in a June 5, 1977 interview) describes his stylistic debt to John McKenna whose records he heard at home in Annagh Beg, Co. Sligo before immigrating to Philadelphia in 1950. Likewise, Moloney sought out Al Purcell, a student of the great Leo Rowsome in Dublin. In 1978 Purcell was a wooden model maker for General Motors in Detroit, who not only played and taught the uilleann pipes but repaired and made reeds for them as well. Liz Carroll was first recorded by Moloney in 1976, just after winning the All-Ireland Senior Championship on the fiddle at age eighteen. A native of Chicago and a composer often compared with Ed Reavy, Carroll learned from older musicians like fiddler Johnny McGreevy. McGreevy (b. 1919), uilleann piper Joe Shannon (b. 1919) and pianist Eleanor Kane Neary (b. 1915) are among the Chicago musicians Dr. Moloney frequently recorded. Neary, who played at the 1934 World's Fair, made only one 78rpm solo recording that was commercially released; the Moloney Collection has over eight hours of her performances.
  Others notable players recorded by Mick Moloney in private settings include fiddlers Paddy Cronin, Andy McGann, Paddy Reynolds and Eugene O'Donnell; flute players Mike Rafferty, Noel Rice, and Richard Hughes; uilleann pipers Tim Britton, Bill Ochs, Jerry O'Sullivan and Joe McKenna; Paddy O'Brien and Gene Kelly, accordion; concertina player Fr. Charlie Coen; and sean nós singer Paddy Tunney. Mary Cooley from Chicago was among the first women artists recorded by Mick Moloney; he documented her talent in 1978 shortly after she had won the 1977 All-Ireland Championship in Ladies Irish Singing.
  Mick Moloney also made contact with American musicians who were developing interests in Irish traditional music, such as the folklorist I. Sheldon Posen and guitarist Duck Baker. Posen made a 1977 recording that was eventually included on an album Moloney produced in 1991 (The Music of Ed Reavy), while Baker recorded tunes that later appeared on his 1979 album Irish Reels, Jigs, Hornpipes and Airs.
  Many other recording sessions including out-takes, alternate cuts, rough mixes and unreleased albums are to be found in this part of the collection. These include projects by Maureen and John Fitzpatrick, Sean McGlynn and Mike Flynn, Gus Collins, Joe Ryan and Eddie Clarke, James Keane and Jack and Fr. Charlie Coen.
  Among the interviews that are of historic importance, are composer/entertainer Shay Healy (b. 1943) who was working in Nashville in 1974; Dennis Clark (1927–1993), historian of the Irish in America, recorded in 1978 at the height of the "roots" phenomena; sean nós singer Joe Heaney (1919–1984) interviewed in 1981 and 1982 while living in Bay Ridge, Brooklyn; the 1977 reflections of banjo player Mike Flanagan (1898–1990) of the Flanagan Brothers, popular recording artists of the 1920s and early 1930s; Mickey Carton, Mary Carton, and Ruthie Morrissey reminiscing in 1982 about their career on the Rockaway cabaret circuit; Eileen McNulty, last surviving member of the Famous McNulty Family; Arthur Godfrey Show regular Carmel Quinn; Clare fiddler Junior Crehan while on tour of the United States in 1976; "Cuz" Teehan, the Chicago accordion and concertina player, speaking in 1976 with Mick Moloney and Irish broadcaster and music collector Ciarán MacMathúna; the three founders of the Irish Musicians Association interviewed in 1977 in the cities where they each set up branches: Ed Reavy (Philadelphia), Louis Quinn (New York), and Frank Thornton (Chicago); three radio hosts, Tommy Caulfield and Will Regan (both Philadelphia) and Dorothy Hayden Cudahy (New York City); a 1977 interview with Pat Roche, founder of the Harp and Shamrock School of Traditional Dance in Chicago; a March 1990 interview with Irish folk singer Paddy Clancy (1922-1998) when he was in Willow Grove, PA. and a 1991 interview with Tommy Makem (1932-2007) in San Francisco.
  Some of the interviews were recorded as source material for liner notes written by Mick Moloney, particularly for Jack and Charlie Coen's 1977 album The Branch Line (Topic), The Martin Mulvihill School - Irish Music: The Living Tradition (Green Linnet, 1977), Johnny Cronin and Joe Burke (Shanachie, 1977), and The Corner House by the Irish Tradition (Green Linnet, 1978).
  There are a few exceptions to the Irish-American focus of these field recordings such as a private performance by the Co. Clare fiddler Bobby Casey (1926-2000), recorded in London in 1973, and private performances by famed Ballinakill flute player, Eddie Moloney. Some of these recordings were probably not recorded by Moloney but ended up in his possession and are included here. Other examples of tapes inherited by Moloney include early compilation tapes made by the composer Ed Reavy (1897–1988) and accordionist, Charlie Mulvihill (1917-1975). These include several examples of private performances and home-made 78rpm recordings transferred to tape, which were then circulated among musicians in the United States during the 1950s and 1960s.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically by artist's last name.
  - Baker, Duck (guitar) Recording session and interview in Philadelphia, PA. for the 1979 Kicking Mule release, Irish Reels, Jigs, Hornpipes and Airs. (Two CDs – Total length: 00:13:57) aiamm301R, Jul 23, 1978; aiamm301R (Box 33, Box 12, Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Baker, Duck (guitar). aiamm625R, Apr 9, 1979; aiamm625R (Box 66, Box 75)
  - Belt, Alan (dancer) Interview with twenty year old member of the Green Grass Clogger dance troupe (15 minutes) followed by Moloney practicing his own composition on mandolin (5 minutes). (Total length: 00:20:00) aiamm591C, Jun 22, 1983; aiamm591C (Box 42, Cd aiamm591C, Box 83, Audiocassette aiamm591C)
  - Blarney (group) Demo of one song, "Lady Elgin," by Milwaukee, WI band featuring Chuck Ward. (Length: 00:05:00) aiamm592C, undated; aiamm592C (Box 42, Cd aiamm592C, Box 83, Audiocassette aiamm592C)
  - Blended Scotch (group) 8-track reel labeled "Welcome Royal Charlie." aiamm346R, undated; aiamm346R (Box 36, Box 21)
  - Bradshaw's Vaudeville Demo. aiamm1443C, undated; aiamm1443C (Box 70, Box 44)
  - Brittingham, Frank (pub owner). Interview recorded in Brittingham's Irish Pub and Restaurant, Lafayette Hill, PA. Brittingham discusses his personal history and his pub, a venue for Irish music in the Philadelphia area. (Two CDs – Total length: 01:04:17) aiamm344C, May 15, 1991; aiamm344C (Box 13, Box 34, Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Britton, Tim (uilleann pipes) Recording session at Mick Moloney's home, 5321 Germantown Ave., Philadelphia, PA. for the 1979 Rounder release, Light Through the Leaves. (One CD – Length: 00:18:36) aiamm269R, Jan 29, 1977; aiamm269R (Box 33, Box 1, Folder 3, Box 12)
  - Britton, Tim (uilleann pipes) Recording session and interview in Philadelphia, PA. (Four CDs – Total length: 00:42:28) aiamm266R, 267R, 268R, Jan 3, 1980; aiamm266R, aiamm267R, aiamm268R (Box 1, Folder 4, Box 12, Box 33)
  - Brown, Rev. Tommy (gospel singer) Interview in Delaware, MD. (Length: 01:00:00) aiamm593C, May 27, 1993; aiamm593C (Box 42, Cd aiamm593C, Box 83, Audiocassette aiamm593C)
  - Buddy and Maybelle. aiamm1386C, 1986; aiamm1386C (Box 71, Box 44)
  - Burke, Joe "Banjo" (banjo and voice, b. 1946, Johnstown, Co. Kilkenny, d. Dec, 2003, Albany, New York) Interview at the Bunratty Pub, Bronx, NY. Burke provides biographical and musical information for the sleeve notes of his 1977 Shanachie recording with fiddler Johnny Cronin. (One CD – Length: 00:19:53) aiamm134R, Feb 18, 1977; aiamm134R (Box 31, Box 1, Folder 5, Box 9)
  - Burke, Joe (accordion, b. Kilnadeema, Loughrea, Galway) Interview in St. Louis, MO. Influential accordionist Burke discusses his life and music. (Length: 00:25:00) aiamm594c, Jun 22, 1984; aiamm594c (Box 25, Box 36)
  - Byrne, Tom (flute, b. May 28, 1920, Co.Sligo) Interview in Cleveland, OH. Byrne discusses his personal and musical experiences in Ireland and Cleveland. (One CD – Length: 00:52:10) aiamm2R, Apr 27, 1980; aiamm2R (Box 8, Box 28, Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Byrne, Tom (flute, b. May 28, 1920, Co.Sligo), McCaffrey, Tom (fiddle, b. 1916, Co. Leitrim) and Noonan, Jimmy (flute, b. 1963, Cleveland, OH) Interview in Cleveland, OH. Byrne and McCaffrey, mainstays of the Cleveland Irish music community, and teenaged Noonan discuss: their personal and musical histories, Irish music in Cleveland. (Three CDs – Total length 01:38:20) aiamm2R, 3R, Apr 27, 1980; aiamm2R, aiamm3R (Box 28, Box 8, Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Byrnes, Tommy (pipes, vocals) Low-fi demo of Scottish band featuring bass and drums. (Length: 00:30:00) aiamm595C, undated; aiamm595C (Box 25, Box 77)
  - Cagney, Dinny. aiamm1378C, Jun 11, 1975; aiamm1378C (Box 71, Box 44)
  - Cahill, Eddie (flute, b. Annagh Beg, Co. Sligo), Vesey, John (fiddle, b. Apr 21, 1924, Ballincurry, Co. Sligo, d. 1995), Moloney, Mick (guitar, b. Nov 15, 1944, Co. Limerick) Recording session in Philadelphia. Musician, collector and scholar Moloney is a National Heritage Fellowship recipient. (One CD – Length 00:22:59) aiamm114R, Feb 6, 1977; aiamm114R (Box 31, Box 9, Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cahill, Eddie (flute) Labeled "Master Tape." aiamm348R, undated; aiamm348R (Box 55, Box 17)
  - Cahill, Eddie (flute) Private performance of traditional music and interview recorded in Philadelphia. Sligo style flute player Cahill briefly plays then discusses: his personal and musical history, the Sligo style, Irish music in Philadelphia. (One CD – Length 00:33:10) aiamm5R, Jun 5, 1977; aiamm5R (Box 8, Box 1, Folder 9, Box 28)
  - Cahill, Eddie (flute), Moloney, Mick (guitar) aiamm598C, undated; aiamm598C (Box 27, Box 77)
  - Cahill, Eddie (flute), Moloney, Mick (mandolin) Private informal performance of tunes. (Length: 00:15:00) aiamm347R, Jun 5, 1977; aiamm347R (Box 36, Box 14)
  - Cahill, Eddie (flute), Moloney, Mick (guitar) Recording session in Philadelphia. (One CD – Length 00:23:28) aiamm115R, Oct 7, 1977; aiamm115R (Box 31, Box 9, Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Cahill, Eddie (flute), Moloney, Mick (guitar), Stoner, Mike (bodhran) Private performance of one tune followed by Monty Python. (Length: 00:05:00) aiamm596C, Nov 27, 1977; aiamm596C (Box 42, Cd aiamm596C, Box 83, Audiocassette aiamm596C)
  - Cahill, Eddie (flute), Moloney, Mick (guitar, banjo), Stoner, Mike (bodhran) Rough mixes. (Length:00:40:00) aiamm597C, undated; aiamm597C (Box 83, Audiocassette aiamm597C, Box 42, Cd aiamm597C)
  - Cahill, Eddie (flute), Stoner, Mike (bodhran) Private performance of traditional music recorded in Philadelphia. (One CD – Length 00:06:09) aiamm115R, Oct 20, 1977; aiamm115R (Box 31, Box 9, Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cahill, Eddie (flute), Moloney, Mick (guitar, mandolin and bouzouki) Recording session in Philadelphia. (One CD – Length 00:30:27) aiamm116R, Oct 29, 1977; aiamm116R (Box 9, Box 31, Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Cahill, Eddie (flute), Moloney, Mick (bouzouki) Recording session in Philadelphia for the 1979 Shanachie LP, Ah! Surely. (One CD – Length 00:09:04) aiamm6R, Dec 22, 1977; aiamm6R (Box 38, Box 1, Folder 13, Box 8)
  - Cahill, Eddie (flute), Moloney, Mick (bouzouki) Recording session in Philadelphia for the 1979 Shanachie LP, Ah! Surely. (Two CDs – Total length 00:35:12) aiamm6R, 117R, Dec 31, 1977; aiamm6R, aiamm117R (Box 1, Folder 14, Box 8, Box 9, Box 28, Box 31)
  - Cahill, Eddie (flute), Moloney, Mick (guitar and bouzouki) Recording session in Philadelphia for the 1979 Shanachie LP, Ah! Surely. (One CD – Length 00:23:12) aiamm118R, May 6, 1978; aiamm118R (Box 31, Box 1, Folder 15, Box 9)
  - Cahill, Eddie (flute), Moloney, Mick (guitar) Recording session in Philadelphia for the 1979 Shanachie LP, Ah! Surely. (One CD – Length 00:10:03) aiamm119R, Jul 21, 1978; aiamm119R (Box 1, Folder 16, Box 9, Box 31)
  - Campbell, Joan. aiamm1281C, Jul 14, 1994; aiamm1281C (Box 44, Box 66)
  - Campbell, John. aiamm1351C, 1988; aiamm1351C (Box 72, Box 44)
  - Cannon, Sean: Practice, London. aiamm1274C, 1973; aiamm1274C (Box 44, Box 65)
  - Side A: Cannon, Sean; Side B: Nick Jones. aiamm1259C, undated; aiamm1259C (Box 66, Box 44)
  - Cappamore (group). aiamm599C, undated; aiamm599C (Box 77, Box 27)
  - Carroll, Liz (fiddle, b. 1957, Chicago, IL) Private performance and interview recorded in Chicago. Traditional music interspersed with discussion of: tunes, Carroll's musical style, influences and peers. (One CD – Length 00:43:50) aiamm9C, Mar 23, 1976; aiamm9C (Box 8, Box 1, Folder 17, Box 34)
  - Carroll, Liz (fiddle). aiamm1409C, 1982; aiamm1409C (Box 44, Box 66)
  - Carroll, Liz (fiddle). aiamm1393C, undated; aiamm1393C (Box 71, Box 44)
  - Carroll, Liz (fiddle). Labeled "Cullowhee Old 78, Unicorn WXPN." aiamm1494C, undated; aiamm1494C (Box 73, Box 45)
  - Carroll, Liz (fiddle) Labeled "Philadelphia." aiamm600C, Apr 5, 1981; aiamm600C (Box 27, Box 55)
  - Carroll, Liz (fiddle) Private performance and interview recorded in Chicago. 1975 All Ireland Senior Fiddle Champion Carroll plays her own compositions and discusses teaching methods, ornamentation, and old-time music. Carroll subsequently received a National Heritage Fellowship. (Two CDs – Total length 00:19:01) aiamm54R, Mar 5, 1978; aiamm54R (Box 29, Box 8, Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Carroll, Liz (fiddle, whistle), Moloney, Mick (banjo). Private performance of traditional music recorded in [?]. (One CD – Length: 00:27:12) aiamm343C, Feb 29, 1979; aiamm343C (Box 13, Box 1, Folder 19, Box 34)
  - Carroll, Liz (fiddle) Workshop. Private fiddle instruction recorded at 20 Harvey St., Philadelphia, PA. (One CD – Length: 00:45:07) aiamm299C, Apr 5, 1981; aiamm299C (Box 1, Folder 20, Box 34, Box 12)
  - Carroll, Liz (fiddle) Private performance of traditional music recorded in [Philadelphia, PA.?] (One CD – Length: 00:20:43) aiamm311C, Aug 10, 1982; aiamm311C (Box 12, Box 1, Folder 21, Box 34)
  - Carroll, Liz (accordion, whistle) Private performance of traditional music played by Carroll on instruments not normally associated with her. (One CD – Length: 00:08:07) aiamm138R, Jan, 1983; aiamm138R (Box 10, Box 31, Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Carroll, Liz (fiddle), Barnett, Armon (fiddle), Moloney, Mick (Guitar) Recording session of Reavy music in Chicago, IL. (Length 00:30:00) aiamm350R, Apr 6; aiamm350R (Box 14, Box 36)
  - Carroll, Liz (fiddle), Moloney, Mick (guitar). aiamm606C, undated; aiamm606C (Box 77, Box 27)
  - Carroll, Liz (fiddle), Moloney, Mick (guitar) Practice. Carroll and Moloney recorded in Philadelphia, PA. practicing tunes. Original tape labeled "Practice". (One CD – Length: 00:51:27) aiamm300C, Jul 27, 1983; aiamm300C (Box 1, Folder 23, Box 12, Box 34)
  - Carroll, Liz (fiddle), Keane, Jimmy (accordion) Labeled "Copy #22." aiamm349R, Jan 24, 1976; aiamm349R (Box 77, Box 17)
  - Carroll, Liz (fiddle), Keane, Jimmy (accordion) Private solo performances including Sean McGlynn's waltzes. Labeled "West Coast 85." (Length: 00:20:00) aiamm601C, 1985; aiamm601C (Box 42, Cd aiamm601C, Box 83, Audiocassette aiamm601C)
  - Carroll, Liz (fiddle), Keane, Jimmy (accordion), Moloney, Mick (banjo) Unidentified (uilleann pipes) Private performances including "McGlynn's Waltz." (Length: 00:30:00) aiamm605C, undated; aiamm605C (Box 42, Cd aiamm605C, Box 83, Audiocassette aiamm605C)